As you create documents you will then
need to save them
in a suitable location on your computer.
You may also need to take some screen
prints and folders
to provide evidence of work that you
have done
and obviously you can open existing
files that you have saved.
On a mac the first thing to do with
regards to saving your files
so I have a sample document on the
screen in front of me
I simply need to go to the file
on save as
once I have selected that I have the the
name of the document
and i'm quite happy for it to be saved
by that and then you have the the
location here so the dropbox
so what i'm going to do is I want to
save this document into
my documents folder and
I haven't got a folder in there at the
moment so what i'm going to do is I'm
going to create a new folder
and call that IT2
and then click create and
i can then save that document inside of
the itq folder
and just as a another point the file
format there
it is saved as a docx file which is
opened by any version of word other than
very early versions if you wanted to
save a document that could be opened by
very early versions of word you would
need to save it as a word 97 to 2004
other alternatives are word template
word 97 to 2004 template and rich text
format
sometimes if you're not sure what sort
of word processor that
somebody may have if you saved it as
rich text format that would be opened by
any so it could be open office apache
office
it will open any version of rich text
format
so once i've done that I can select save
and that is then saved in that folder
as you work through the it course during
your assessment you will be asked to
provide screenshots
to evidence certain tasks that you have
completed
to take a screenshot on a mac you quite
simply need to find the folder or the
document that you wish to take a
screenshot off
make sure that it is displayed clearly
on the screen and there are two options
you can take a snapshot of the
everything that's on the screen at that
moment in time or you can specify
a specific area to take a snapshot of
exactly what's on the screen at that
time
you can press the shift key
and the command key and hold those down
and then press the
number three you will hear the sound of
a camera clicking which indicates that
it has taken the screenshot
you can then go to the word document
in this example i'm just using a blank
one book when you're providing
screenshots it will primarily be in your
assessment
booklet so what I need to do then is
hold down the control key and press v
and that will provide a screenshot so
it's basically took a picture of what
was on the screen
and that has now been entered into the
document
one of the benefits of organizing fails
is that it makes it much easier to find
the files again when you need to
continue working with them
alternatively you can access files
directly from a program
in this demonstration i'm just going to
give an example of how I can access
files so I know I have files saved in my
itq
folder on the my documents and
there's a letter in there and if i
wanted to open it I would just double
click and open it
another way that this can be done is
when in word
i can simply bring up the word document
and then go to file
and open again and
i navigate to the itq folder double
click on that
and that will then open the form
document as you can see
any time I wish to see if that I don't
need to now save as
when I save that file I can just go to
fail and see if
or again I can press the command key in
the s key hold down command press s
and that will save it it only need to
save as
if i'm changing the name of the document
or I want to save another copy